Azhar Khan

Karāchi, Sindh, Pakistan



iazharkhann@gmail.com



0331-2372239



linkedin.com/in/azhar-khan-05b458161

Summary

With over 5 years of experience in HR, I am adept at enhancing the employee experience and developing positive workplace cultures. Since 2017, I have been employed in HR management for FMCG, Electronics, Insurance and Textile Industry. In 2020, I won the company's prestigious award for HR Professional of the Year.

Specialization: Human resource Operations, compensation & benefits, talent management, recruitment, onboarding, employment contract management, coaching.

Experience



Human Resources Specialist

Star Textile (PVT) LTD

Dec 2022 - Present (2 months)

Hiring for overall Star Group (Oaks, Eximpo & Yarana Textile).

Attracting and retaining best talent.

Managing Employer branding using multiple techniques and platforms.

Responsible for backend HR operations (Leave and Attendance Management).

Assistant Manager Human Resources

Premier Insurance Limited

May 2020 - Nov 2022 (2 years 7 months)

Leave and attendance system, review daily attendance record, monthly pay deduction against excess

Maintain Employee Data, joining & deletion, completion of employee files and periodic review to update the employee records.

Verification from previous employers/other references.

Monthly Benefits Reimbursement including fuel, mobile and medical allowance/bills.

Monthly PSO payments, close and issuance of new PSO fuel cards.

Processing of new medical cards through Health Department.

Training & Development.

Legal issues and payments under guidance from Department Head.



Kenwood - HR Officer

R&I Electrical Appliances (Pvt.) Ltd.

Feb 2019 - May 2020 (1 year 4 months)

Compilation of Monthly attendance of Permanent and contractual staff.

Preparing final settlements of separated employees.

Responsible for timely execution of Health Insurance Cases.

Responsible for managing the leaves of employee and maintain its database on monthly basis.

Preparing different types of reports i.e.: (staff turnover, Health Insurance & Final Settlements)

Executive Human Resources

Shan Foods Private Limited

Jan 2018 - Oct 2018 (10 months)

Responsible for the HR dealing of entire SHAN FOOD's Labor. (Hiring, Account opening and labor legal issues)

Prepare Statistics Reports of labor attendance on daily, weekly and monthly basis.

Full command on HR related software (SOFTRACK)

Prepare payrolls and carry out salary disbursement activity

Maintenance of leaves, attendance, shifts and final settlement of employees

Report Analyst

TAG Group Sep 2017 - Jan 2018 (5 months)

Education



Karachi University

Bachelor of Science - BSc, Actuarial Science 2014 - 2020

Skills

Talent Management • Technical Recruiting • Employer Branding • People Management • HR Operations • Technical Recruitment • Financial Reporting • Statistical Data Analysis • Microsoft Office • Multi-task & Handle High-volume Workloads